OpenClaw is the most powerful AI agent
framework in the world right now and
it's about to replace your entire
workflow. While everyone else is still
prompting chat GPT one message at a
time, you could be running a specialized
team of AI agents that work for you
24/7, remember everything, and cost
significantly less than a full-time
employee to operate. The problem is
there are a lot of tutorials out there
showing you how to set up Open Claw on a
Mac Mini or VPS, but nobody's showing
you how to actually get it to do
anything. I spent over $200 in the last
48 hours stress testing the system so
you don't have to. In this video, I'm
going to show you how to set up the chat
model so you don't break the bank, how
to deploy a self-healing team of AI
agents that communicate with each other,
and how to set up the infrastructure
that lets your AI run on autopilot. And
if we haven't met yet, my name is Duncan
Rogoff. I'm a former art director for
brands like Apple, PlayStation, and
Nissan. And I now run a six-figure AI
agency. In under 12 months, I've grown a
following of over 110,000 people, and I
lead a community called the Buildroom
where more than 2,000 are already using
AI to grow their audience and generate
leads for their business in under 3
hours per week. So, focus in, close all
your tabs, and let's build. So, here we
are inside of OpenClaw, and it's not
always the sexiest to look at, but today
I really want to cover like the most
impactful things that I've set up that
actually help me run my business. These
are a couple things like communicating
with it, using Telegram, setting up
different LLM models to handle different
tasks so I can save on cost, like using
cron job to just tackle tasks like a
daily morning briefing or saving this to
GitHub or things like that. And then a
breakdown of how I've set up my AI agent
orchestras
we have the orchestrator agent that
communicates with all the other agents
which really allows us to be as
efficient as we possibly can be. I'll
probably bounce back and forth between
openclaw and some slides I have prepared
because like I said openclaw isn't the
prettiest to look at, but I do want you
to understand where everything lives.
Now when you first get into openclaw, it
is essentially a baby. It knows nothing.
So it is really up to you to configure
this the right way and there's not a lot
of information out there on how to do
it. So there are a couple things that
I've learned that have actually been
really really impactful for me. So the
very first thing that is really helpful
is actually setting up different LLM
models for different tasks. So let me
just show you what I mean. Can you tell
me which LLM models we are using and for
what tasks? So now I can just
communicate with Open Claw directly here
in the chat in the browser and basically
it's showing me that now I've actually
switched between a couple of different
models depending on the complexity.
Right? So for here we can say the
default for everyday task we're using
Gemini 3 or Flash preview which like
gives me a 90% cost reduction. So when
I'm just chatting back and forth with
the agent itself it's using Gemini which
is super super cheap to use. Then from
there for any of the content sub agents
we're using like a step up model Claude
Sonnet 4.5 which is like a really great
model we're using for lead magnet and
writing and our LinkedIn post because
Claude is super super good at writing.
And then for the most expert layer,
we're switching dynamically to Claude
Opus 4.6, which is the latest anthropic
model. It's the most expensive to use,
but it's the best at complex reasoning
or complex tasks like coding or
automation builds or any sort of
multi-step reasoning. And so basically,
you can just talk to OpenClaw like it's
a smart assistant and tell it to figure
it out. Like you can just say to it
things like, "Hey, I want you to set up
different LLM models for different
tasks. Use Gemini for this, Sonnet for
that, and Claude Opus for this." And
then that way you can actually save on
cost instead of relying on heavier and
expensive models for everything. One
other super valuable setup hack is
switching between your Claude Max plan
and the API like dynamically and
intelligently. Can you tell me how we
are intelligently switching between the
Cloud Max and the API? So basically
there has been like a lot of chatter
right now about how Quad or Anthropic is
banning people who are using the Claude
Max subscription in OpenClaw because
it's just kind of like racking up the
credit so to speak. But we basically are
able to integrate a system that will
dynamically switch between the two. So
as you start to hit rate limits on your
Quad Max plan, it'll dynamically switch
over to the API when needed. So this is
essentially how it's doing it.
Basically, it just uses the Quad Max
plan first. Right now, I'm just paying
$100 a month cuz I'm not ramping this up
like crazy. And then once you start to
kind of like hit those rate limits,
it'll switch over to the API because the
API does end up actually being really
expensive if you're only using that. If
you need to know how to get access to
your max plan on OpenClaw, literally
just ask. It walked me through the setup
and how to get my Quad Max API key in
like two seconds. The next is a
directive that I actually got from a
friend. Can you tell me about the figure
it out directive? So basically, this is
just like an instruction to OpenClaw to
basically just like be smart, figure it
out. If I ask you to do something, just
like handle it. So I don't have to have
this constant like back and forth with
OpenClaw to actually execute on
something. You can see here it's the
core operator philosophy. Basically, I
can't is not vocabulary. If I don't know
something, learn it now. So, this way
I'm not constantly having to like baby
open claw. It's just going to go out if
it doesn't know how to solve a problem.
It's going to research the internet and
figure out how to solve something. It's
going to search for docs or tutorials.
It's going to reverse engineer stuff.
It's going to look at APIs, right? It's
going to try multiple approaches to
actually solve the problem first before
coming to me and asking me questions.
That way I don't have to hold his hand
through everything. So if you want just
pause this, take a screenshot here, drop
it into openclaw and say, "Hey, like
this is how I want you to behave." This
has actually saved me a lot of time. So
now the next thing to understand is
basically the agents infrastructure.
This is kind of like having OpenClaw act
as like a different team of sub agents.
And this will allow you to save on costs
and be as efficient as possible. Cuz
what I was finding is that if you're
just doing everything with a single
agent in the main chat, it gets really
bloated really quickly. it tends to
drift or hallucinate. You're constantly
having to like restart the chat new. Oh,
one thing that's also helpful in the
chat. If you just type slash new, you
can basically start a new session. It'll
clear the memory or the cache and
basically gets rid of all the previous
context. So that way you don't have kind
of that bloat and that drift happening.
There is a really clear sort of
orchestrator pattern that's been
developed with all of these AI agents in
general where you have kind of like the
orchestrator at the top level and then
it speaks to all of the other agents
beneath it and tells them how to
communicate with each other. I put
together this little guide about the
ultimate guide to just multi- aent
systems like how to set these up, how to
design like a sub agent, especially for
OpenClaw using the soul.md file. I'll
leave a link in the description where
you can just get that totally free so
you can have access to this. The most
important thing inside of these agents
to pay attention to is these files. So,
there's an agent soul tools file. I'm
going to walk you through what each one
of those is so you understand. And
basically, I found that not every agent
needs all of these files. Basically, you
have me. I just have my Duncan agent as
the main agent. And this has access to
everything. And then it just essentially
provides all of the sub agents with the
context that they need and nothing else.
So again, you're not sending extra
tokens to the LLMs to process. You're
only sending exactly what it needs. So
first is the soul.md file. This is the
brain. This is the agents identity and
the core instructions. It defines who it
is, how it behaves, and crucial
behavioral boundaries. So like what to
do and what not to do. So if we come in
here to the solemn MD file here, this is
just for my main agent, right? You're a
Duncan's orchestrator agent. You do not
execute tasks yourself. You route them.
So you're a task router and coordinator.
You basically need to identify which sub
agent should handle the task. You should
spawn that sub agent with a clear
complete task description and then
report back the results when they
arrive. So again, it's this two-way
communication between the orchestrator
and then the agents that live beneath
it. These are the tasks that we expect
it to delegate. And then these are the
kind of tasks that we expect the agent
just to handle itself without having to
call a sub agent. Inside the community,
I do have this AI agent dream team stack
which comes set with all of these
prompts for an orchestrator, a
researcher, writer, chief of staff, and
a builder to do code and things for you.
It comes with a prompt and so basically
you could just come down here and copy
this entire prompt into openclaw and
it'll set up this entire agent
architecture for you. And so the next
file to understand is this agents.md
file. This is the directory of all of
the sub aents that we create. And so it
lists each of the sub aents and the
specific roles and their strength. So
this is an example of the type of file
that only your orchestrator agent needs.
It basically goes ahead and it just
describes each of the sub aents. And so
basically the orchestrator needs to
understand what each of the sub aents
are like something that creates
Instagram and Tik Tok carousels,
something that writes Twitter threads,
something that generates images or like
basically creates lead magnets for me,
right? So it's really clear what each of
the sub aents do. So the orchestrator
understands which agents to call for
what task. But this is a really good
example like inside of like my carousel
creator, there is no agents.md file
because the carousel creator doesn't
need to understand the agents around it
because that's a job for the
orchestrator. So we're not sending
additional context that the sub agent
doesn't need. The next file you need to
understand is this tools file. And this
is just basically anything that your
agent needs to execute on its task. So
it doesn't need access to things like
GitHub or NADN. For me, I gave the
carousel creator access to like images
of me so that it knows what I look like.
So therefore can pass my image to Nano
Banana to generate images. And then any
information about the process itself,
right? Do we have a specific structure
for in my case like this set of slides,
right? And then here I give it access to
notion so that it can connect to notion.
And once it's done creating a carousel,
it can basically save it inside of
notion for me so that I can have access
to it and review it. There is a file in
there called identity MD. I don't really
use it too much, but if you want your
agent to have like a specific identity
or behave a certain way or have certain
properties or characteristics, this is
where you would create that information.
And again, you can always tell OpenClaw
to create it for itself. The user.md
file is everything about you, the
operator, the founder, whatever it is,
right? So, this is everything about you.
So, the agent will read this to
understand like how it should
communicate or how it should behave or
how it should write or things like that.
And the last one that is arguably one of
the most important is memory.md. This is
like the long-term knowledge. So this
will actually get updated automatically
by openclaw the more you interact with
the system and the more information it
has about you and your processes and the
way that you like to work. So we can see
here that this has a ton and ton of
information about me like the technical
stack that I like to use some
information about my philosophy and
things like that who I collaborate with
all of my social proof how I like to
operate all of these things. These are
super super detailed. But if we come
down here like into the carousel, you
can see I don't have the memory in here
because I'm leaving it up to the
orchestrator to decide which pieces of
information should get passed to any of
the sub agents. So again, we're not
overloading the system. If you're trying
to figure out how you can create all of
that information easily, I have this
great prompt which is to create a data
packet of information about yourself. If
you've been talking with Claude or if
you've been talking with Chatbt, you
would just come over to one of those
LLMs and paste this in and you're just
going to get basically a giant PDF full
of information about your business, the
projects you've worked on, your goals,
your communication style, and things
like that. And you can just copy and
paste that information into OpenCL and
say, "Hey, here's everything you need to
know about me. What should we do with
this?" So setting up these agents the
right way in the beginning is extremely
impactful to the efficiency of your
system and it's going to save you so
much headache in the long run. Before I
show you the jobs that I have OpenClaw
doing for me automatically, one of the
first things you should do is set it up
to communicate with you via Telegram or
WhatsApp. So that way you can take this
on the go. So I was actually out this
morning and I was texting with OpenClaw
and I was asking it to create that kind
of AI dream team starter pack for all of
you guys. So basically, you can see here
I just had it say, can you create one
thorough master prompt that would
instantly deploy and set up a team of
powerful agents for anyone? And then
said, hey, I love this idea. A starter
team can deploy. Here are the four sub
agents, the researcher, the writer, the
chief of staff, and the builder. They do
all of this. And basically what it went
ahead and did is it created this entire
document for me in notion. I didn't
write this. I didn't type this in. It
figured it out. It organized this. It
did all the design. It created this
prompt for me and for you guys. It's
just a massive, massive timesaver. So,
the other way I like to use this for my
business is there are a couple of what
are called cron jobs and they're called
cron because it has to do with, you
know, chronological or time. These are
basically just jobs that will run on a
schedule. And this is generally like
pretty ugly to look at, but you can just
talk to openclaw and say, "Hey, I need
something that does xyz." One of the
first things I had it build was this
idea of a morning briefing. So, every
day when I wake up, I actually have a
message inside of Telegram. It looks
like this. It basically gives me
yesterday's progress like what we
accomplished yesterday, what we have to
prioritize today, anything like any
pending decisions, like any feedback
that it needs from me and then it
basically just sends this to Telegram.
So you can see here that it says here's
the top three today. I should post a new
carousel to Tik Tok or Instagram. I
should write a new Twitter thread and I
should basically just test the setup
guide end to end. Here are the tasks.
These are open clause tasks. It's going
to monitor Twitter for any auto replies.
And so basically if I have lead magnet
posts on Twitter, it's going to
recognize when somebody like comments
the word AI and it's automatically going
to DM them for me and send them whatever
the lead magnet is. And so here the
quick decision section is basically
feedback that it needs for me like yes
or no. Do I want to add a hosting or
affiliate link to my setup guide? Like
yeah, for sure let's do that. Do I want
to ship a Twitter thread today or do I
want to wait for something else to be
done? Right? And then I also had it just
like give me ideas like based off the
conversations we've been having, what
we've been building, like here are some
growth ideas to help the business grow,
help the community grow, all of those
good things. So, do I want to create a
quality control miniourse for the build
room? Do I want to turn the open claw
setup into a YouTube tutorial series
like we're doing right now? Do I want to
cross-promote the comment content
engine, which is basically like a little
micro SAS app I built the other day?
Pretty cool. So, this will just run
every day at 7 a.m. So, if there's like
a structure that you want for this, just
tell Open Call, hey, I want a daily
morning briefing at 7 a.m. Send me these
things. On the flip side, I had it
actually create this midnight daily
tracker. It's basically just going to
review what we did for that day, and
it's just going to log everything in
notion for me. So, that way I just have
something to reflect back on. I can use
this for content. I can use this for
marketing. It's just for my kind of
keeping to understand what we've done.
So you can see here we can see like
here's what we accomplished like cost
optimization strategy for Tik Tok
carousels, content brief, here are the
key decisions that we made about like
aesthetics and my brand, right? And
here's what's kind of in progress or
what's blocked. Here are all the skills
and files that we created. And so again,
this is just a way for me to keep track
of everything that we've been building.
This one's honestly a lifesaver. You can
just create a repository on GitHub and
you can just say, "Hey, OpenCaw, I need
you to back up all of our code into
GitHub every day." And so this way all
of your configuration files, your memory
scripts, everything is just pushed to
GitHub. So that way if anything breaks
or you're just running into problems,
you can instantly roll it back to the
repository. So to a working state. If
you want access to my AI Dream Team
prompt library and autopilot stack, it's
inside the buildroom. All you have to do
is come into the lesson, open this up,
and I give you ready to deploy, copy,
and paste prompts so you can set up all
of these agents and cron jobs just like
I have. All right, back to it. And
arguably the most impactful cron job I
have set to run every week. It is this
weekly trends analysis report. It's
basically going to look at Reddit,
YouTube, and X to figure out what people
are actually talking about based off of
kind of some keywords, my audience, my
ICP, their pain points, and things like
that. And so gives me like a top pick
like content idea number one. I gave
Open Claw full access to my consulting
business. Basically, OpenClaw is the
viral moment right now, which is why I'm
talking about it in this video. It gives
me a full execution strategy. It gives
me more content ideas based off of kind
of the findings from the different
channels. Gives me some opportunities to
create different lead magnets for my
audience. So again, I can send this
information to my lead magnet sub agent
to create them for me. And it's going to
go ahead and rank all this content for
me. It's going to break it down by
different platforms like different
platforms, LinkedIn posts, YouTube
videos, short form videos, any like
audience language that I can like kind
of pull in, right? any pain points and
objections that I can really hit on so
that I'm speaking directly to my
audience's frustrations. And so this is
probably one of the most impactful
things that I have created. And then at
the bottom, it just kind of links to all
the sources that it pulled from. If you
want to get access to any of the prompts
that we use today or learn how to build
a highly profitable personal brand using
AI, just check the link in the
description to join thousands of other
people inside the buildroom. If you
think open claw is cool, just check out
this video up here of 63 insane use
cases that other people are doing.